RYAN GOWARD

Game Designer

ABOUT

Ambitious designer with 8 years of professional experience and over 10 years and +100,000 downloads of indie experience.

Having worked at studios in the UK, US and Japan, I've shipped titles in Unreal and Unity and have been involved in both creating content as well as establishing studio practice and pipelines.

My passion is combining Character, Camera and Controls in atmospheric environments.

SKILLS

- 6 years experience in Unity and C# for both gameplay content and tools
- 4 years experience in Unreal using Blueprint and Bluetility
- Strong experience with owning, designing and implementing features
- Strong experience of leading interdisciplinary and international comms to ensure content aligns with project goals
- 3 years of Blender and Substance experience

LANGUAGES

English - Native German - Native

Japanese - N2 Equivalent

CONTACT

ryangoward.com ryn.goward@gmail.com https://ryangoward.itch.io/

WORK EXPERIENCE

17-Bit - Kyoto, Japan [October 2023 - Present]

Level Designer - Awaysis

- Established flexible and efficient level design pipeline for team of contractors
- Created detailed yet easy to digest documentation
- Designed and built 3D levels and Dev Tools in UE5

Skeleton Crew Studios - Kyoto, Japan [Feb 2023 - Oct 2023]

Game Designer & Producer - Ninja Slayer

- Designed and built 3D levels, boss fights and gimmicks in UE5 to match client specifications.
- Coordinate production between JP and ENG team members
- Helped establish pipeline, documentation and tools

Abertay Game Lab - Dundee, Scotland [2018]

QA testing - Skye Tales, Becket

• Tested products and tracked bugs using Bugzill and Jira

Outplay Entertainment - Dundee, Scotland [Sep 2017 - Dec 2017] Localization (Contract) - Zen Words, 2 Photos 1 Word

- Localised mobile games between German and English
- Helped design and implement levels and puzzles

Insane Mind Games - California, U.S.A. [Aug 2016 - Apr 2017] Level Design and Production - Breaking Wheel

- Designed and built 3D levels in UE4
- Helped organize project timeline from start to release

EDUCATION

Abertay University - Dundee, Scotland [2017 - 2021]

BA HONS - Game Design and Production (First Class)

Ayrshire College- Ayr, Scotland [2016 - 2017]

HNC Computer Games Development